http://www.tchabitat.org/privacy-policy?hsLang=en

We are operating virtually until further notice: Read the details. Habitat homeowners: Click for support.
Privacy Policies
Our Website Privacy Policy and Donor Privacy Policy are outlined below.
Privacy Policies
Our Website Privacy Policy and Donor Privacy Policy are outlined below.
Website Privacy Policy
This website policy applies to all visitors to our website.
[Jump to Donor Privacy Policy]
Use of links
On our Website, we provide links to other servers which may contain information of interest to our readers. Although we vet and take caution when sharing, we take no responsibility for, and exercise no control over, the organizations, views, or accuracy of the information contained on other servers.
Creating a text link from your Web site to our site does not require permission. If you have a link you'd like us to consider adding to our Web site, please send an email to webmaster@tchabitat.org with the subject "Link request."
External links in our blog articles should be educational and relevant to the blog content and/or related to Twin Cities Habitat’s mission. Per our current policy, we do not add links to external sites unless they were included in the original post, or we deem the new content would add value, or make the post more evergreen.
Use of text and images
If you would like to publish information that you find on our Website, please send your request to webmaster@tchabitat.org. Where text or images are posted on our site with the permission of the original copyright holder, a copyright statement appears at the bottom of the page.
All photos on this site are owned by Twin Cities Habitat for Humanity unless otherwise noted. These photos are used with permission from both the original photographer and the subjects of the photos (when applicable), and may not be used externally without express written consent from Twin Cities Habitat, the photographer, and the subject of the photo (when applicable).
Use of our logo is prohibited unless granted with express written consent from the Senior Director of Marketing & Communications.
Accessibility
This Website is designed to be accessible to visitors with disabilities, and to comply with federal guidelines concerning accessibility. We use an accessibility tool to run quality assessments of our Website on a regular basis, and we make necessary adjustments and updates to our site, at minimum, on a monthly basis. We welcome your comments. If you have suggestions on how to make the site more accessible, please contact us at webmaster@tchabitat.org.
Website privacy
We have created this statement to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. We do not collect personally identifying information about you when you visit our site, unless you choose to provide such information to us. Providing such information is strictly voluntary. This policy is your guide to how we will handle information we learn about you from your visit to our Website.
Reading or download
We collect and store only the following information about you: the name of the domain from which you access the Internet (for example, comcast.net, if you are connecting from a Comcast account, or umn.edu if you are connecting from the University of Minnesota's domain), the date and time you access our site, and the Internet address of the Website from which you linked to our site.
We use the information we collect to measure the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, and to help us make our site more useful to visitors. We also add your information to applicable opt-in lists, based on the form(s) you submit. This may include regular communications from Twin Cities Habitat via email or print.
Sending us an email
You also may decide to send us personally identifying information, for example, in an electronic mail message containing a question or comment, or by filling out a Web form that provides us this information. We use personally identifying information from email primarily to respond to your requests. We may forward your email to other employees who are better able to answer your questions. We may also use your email to contact you in the future about our programs that may be of interest.
We want to be very clear: We will not obtain personally identifying information about you when you visit our site, unless you choose to provide such information to us. Providing such information is strictly voluntary. Except as might be required by law, we do not share any information we receive with any outside parties.
If you sign up for one of our email lists, we will only send you the kinds of information you have requested. We won't share your name or email address with any outside parties.
Opt out or change your contact information
Our site provides users the opportunity to opt out of receiving communications from us through a special online form you can access through any email you've received from Twin Cities Habitat (link can be found at the bottom of these emails). You may choose to receive only specific communications or none at all. You may also update your contact information previously provided to us through another online form. You cannot remove yourself from our database, but you can prevent unwanted communication. If you have questions or need assistance with updating your communication preferences, or opting out of emails, please send us an email at webmaster@tchabitat.org.
This website uses Google Ads & Facebook Ads
This website uses the Google Ads remarketing service to advertise on third party websites to previous visitors to our site. It could mean that we advertise to previous visitors who haven’t completed a task on our site, for example using the contact form to make an inquiry. This could be in the form of an advertisement on the Google search results page, or a site in the Google Display Network. Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Twin Cities Habitat for Humanity’s website. Of course, any data collected will be used in accordance with our own privacy policy and Google’s privacy policy. You can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Preferences page, and if you want to you can opt out of interest-based advertising entirely by cookie settings or permanently using a browser plugin.
Facebook may use cookies, web beacons, and other storage technologies to collect or receive specific types of information and use that information to provide targeted ads. You may update your preferences on Facebook or notify us via email.
Questions about our policies
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Website, you can contact us at webmaster@tchabitat.org
Donor Privacy Policy
We value our donors, volunteers, and prospects (hereafter referred to as our "supporters") and take their privacy seriously. We will respect the privacy of information that we are privileged to have about our supporters. Our commitment to respect the privacy of our supporters extends to how we obtain, use, protect and share information about them. This privacy policy is intended to be applied in conjunction with related Twin Cities Habitat for Humanity policies, including, but not limited to, our Donor Bill of Rights.
Principles, actions, and beliefs
We will hold strictly all information concerning donors and prospects, including names, addresses, names of beneficiaries, nature and value of estates, amounts of provisions or gifts, etc., unless a donor or prospect grants permission to use selective information for purposes of referral, testimonial, example, recognition, or publicity.
We will not share, sell, rent or otherwise offer information about supporters to other organizations except Habitat for Humanity International.
We contractually require any person or organization providing services to Twin Cities Habitat for Humanity to protect the confidentiality of supporter information.
We have procedures in place to limit access to information to those employees and volunteers who need to know such information in order to fulfill our mission.
We will use our best efforts to comply with the written or oral request of any supporter who does not want their name used in any promotional material, wishes their name removed from solicitation and other mailing lists, or wishes to have their gifts or services be anonymous.
We will collect, use and share information about our supporters among employees and volunteers only on a needs-to-know basis and for the sole purpose of carrying out Twin Cities Habitat’s mission.
Donor Bill of Rights
Philanthropy is based on voluntary action for the common good.  It is a tradition of giving and sharing that is primary to the quality of life. To assure that philanthropy merits the respect and trust of the general public, and that donors and prospective donors can have full confidence in the not-for-profit organizations and causes they are asked to support, we declare that all donors have these rights:
The right to be informed of the organization's mission, of the way the organization intends to use donated resources, and of its capacity to use donations effectively for their intended purposes.
The right to be informed of the identity of those serving on the organization's governing board, and to expect the board to exercise prudent judgment in its stewardship responsibilities.
The right to have access to the organization's most recent audited financial statements.
The right to be assured their gifts will be used for the purposes for which they were given.
The right to receive appropriate acknowledgement and recognition or to remain anonymous if desired.
The right to be assured that information about their donations is handled with respect and with confidentiality to the extent provided by law.
The right to be informed whether those seeking donations are volunteers, employees of the organization or hired solicitors.
The right to ask questions when making a donation and to receive prompt, truthful and forthright answers.
E-Donor Bill of Rights
To be clearly and immediately informed of the organization's name, identity, nonprofit or for-profit status, its mission, and purpose when first accessing the organization's website.
To have easy and clear access to alternative contact information other than through the website or email.
To be assured that all third-party logos, trademarks, trustmarks and other identifying, sponsoring, and/or endorsing symbols displayed on the website are accurate, justified, up-to-date, and clearly explained.
To be informed of whether or not a contribution entitles the donor to a tax deduction, and of all limits on such deduction based on applicable laws.
To be assured that all online transactions and contributions occur through a safe, private, and secure system that protects the donor's personal information.
To be clearly informed if a contribution goes directly to the intended charity, or is held by or transferred through a third party.
To have easy and clear access to an organization's privacy policy posted on its website and be clearly and unambiguously informed about what information an organization is gathering about the donor and how that information will be used.
To be clearly informed of opportunities to opt out of data lists that are sold, shared, rented, or transferred to other organizations.
To not receive unsolicited communications or solicitations unless the donor has "opted in" to receive such materials.
For further information about our Donor Privacy Policy, please contact Kelsey Wotzka, Resource Development Associate, at 612-305-7183 or contribute@tchabitat.org.
Contact Us
Donate
Volunteer
Get Involved
Programs
About
Shop
Twin Cities Habitat for Humanity
St.Paul Address1954 University Avenue WSt. Paul, MN55104
Phone651-207-1700
Business HoursMonday-Friday 8:30 a.m. to 5:00 p.m.
Twin Cities Habitat for Humanity is an Equal Opportunity housing agency and Equal Opportunity Affirmative Action employer. TCHFH Lending, Inc. is an Equal Housing Lender. Twin Cities Habitat for Humanity, Inc. NLMS #400065 TCHFH Lending, Inc. NLMS #1482482
Twin Cities Habitat for Humanity is a 501 (c)(3) non-profit recognized by the IRS. Tax ID Number: 36-3363171. NMLS ID 400065
Twin Cities Habitat for Humanity ReStores
Store Locations & Donation drop-off sites:
New Brighton Address510 County Road D WestNew Brighton, MN 55112
Minneapolis Address2700 Minnehaha AvenueMinneapolis, MN 55406
Phone612-588-3820
Business HoursTuesday-Friday, 12:00 p.m. to 6:00 p.m.Saturday 10:00 a.m. to 4:00 p.m.Sunday & Monday: Closed
© Twin Cities Habitat for Humanity   |   Privacy Policy
